RAMESH ADHIKARI

Augusta, Georgia, USA | radhikari@augusta.edu

Website: ramesh-adhikari.github.io | GitHub:ramesh-adhikari | LinkedIn: adramesh

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Ph.D. student at the School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University, under the guidance of Dr. Costas Busch. My research focuses on Distributed Algorithms and Blockchain Technology. With four years of industry experience as a Software Engineer, I bring both academic expertise and practical knowledge to my work.

EDUCATION

School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University

Ph.D. in Computer and Cyber Sciences

Pokhara University

Masters of Science in Computer Engineering

Tribhuvan University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Augusta, Georgia, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

Kathmandu, Nepal

2018 - 2021

Kathmandu, Nepal

2013 - 2017

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Ramesh Adhikari, and Costas Busch. Lockless Blockchain Sharding with Multiversion Control, SIROCCO 2023 (2023)

Ramesh Adhikari, and Suresh Pokharel. Performance Evaluation of Convolutional Neural Network Using Synthetic Medical Data Augmentation Generated by GAN. International Journal of Image and Graphics (2021): 2350002

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant | Augusta University | Augusta, Georgia, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

Working on the distributed algorithm and blockchain technology, mainly on sharding in blockchain to solve the scalability issue, under the supervision of Dr. Costas Busch.

Graduate Student | Nepal College of Information Technology | Kathmandu, Nepal

2020 - 2021

Worked on machine learning and deep learning projects under faculty members to complete master's research.

SERVICE

- Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (2022)
- Reviewer, The 6th IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain 2023)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Sanima Bank | Kathmandu, Nepal

May 2019 - Jun 2022

- Developed web applications for commercial banks.
- Integrated API and web services.
- Developed Batch Script and SQL query to automate the process.

Software Engineer | SmartMobe Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Kathmandu, Nepal

Feb 2018 - April 2019

- Collaborated with a 30-member team to develop cutting-edge APIs for mobile and web apps.
- Researched new tools and technologies, implementing improvements for efficiency and automation.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND PARTICIPATION

- Attended The Southeast Regional Programming Languages Seminar 2023 (Oct 2023).
- Presented a paper at the 30th International Colloquium on Structural Information and Communication Complexity (SIROCCO 2023) in Alcala De Henares, Madrid, Spain (June 6-9, 2023).
- Received \$1000 travel award from the Graduate School, Augusta University, to present a paper at SIROCCO 2023 (Mar 2023).
- Presented a poster at the 3rd annual workshop on Emerging Data Science Methods for Complex Biomedical and Cyber Data at Augusta University (Mar 2023).
- Received an NSF travel award for the 3rd Data Science Workshop at Augusta University (Feb 2023).
- Attended the International Symposium on Distributed Computing (DISC) conference in 2022, awarded by Augusta University.
- Received the Star Performance Excellence Award at Sanima Bank Ltd (2021).

- Granted a full scholarship for a Master of Science in Computer Engineering from Pokhara University (2018).
- Served as a member of the Kathford FOSS Community at Kathford International College, guiding participants in the EVOLVE 2.0 software competition (2017).
- Achieved First Runner-Up in a software competition at Kantipur Engineering College (2015).

SKILLS

Programming languages, Libraries, Tools: Python | Go | C | C++ | JavaScript | PHP | Tensorflow | MySQL | SQL server | Shell Scripting

Broad Skills: Distributed Algorithm | Distributed System | Blockchains | Algorithmic Analysis | Web Scraping | Database Design | Machine Learning | Cloud Computing | Problem Solving